Guide to the Don Byrd Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Don Byrd papers
1953-2010
YCAL MSS 967
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11.22
(16 boxes)
Byrd, Don, 1944-
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, sketchbooks, notebooks, photographs, audiovisual materials, and other papers that document the work and social circle of poet Don Byrd. Notable correspondents include Charles Bernstein, Clayton Eshleman, Susan Howe, Gerrit Lansing, Paul Metcalf, and Jed Rasula. Photographs include color and black and white portraits of Byrd and other poets. Audiovisual materials consist of audiorecordings made by Byrd of poets including John Ashbery, Charles Bernstein, Gerrit Lansing, Paul Metcalf, Charles Olson, and others.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1953-2002. II. Sketchbooks and notebooks, 1967-2010. III. Photographs, 1970s-1980s. IV. Other papers, 1970s-2010. V. Audiovisual materials, 1960s-1990s.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 14-16 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Biographical / Historical
Don Byrd is an American poet, sound artist, and professor of English at the State University of New York at Albany.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Alfred Z. Baker, Jr. Fund and the Donald Windham-Sandy Campbell Collection Endowment Fund, 2014.
American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Sketchbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Sketchbooks -- United States -- 21st century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Byrd, Don, 1944-; Lansing, Gerrit, 1928-; Metcalf, Paul C., 1917-1999
- Correspondence, 1953-2002; Series I; 5.5; (7 boxes)
  - Abel, David, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Ades, Joan and Richard Edelman, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Charles, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Alpert, Barry, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes "Day of Atonement for Indiana University, Yom Kippur 1977" inscribed to Don Byrd.
  - Amato, Joe and Christopher Fleisher, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Bruce, 1985-1995 (Box 1)
  - Ananstas, Peter, 1970 (Box 1)
  - B General, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Beckett, Tom (Viscerally Press), 1953-1981 (Box 1)
  - Benson, Andrew, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Berge, Carol, circa 1980s (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Charles, 1979-1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bertholf, Robert, 1975-1994; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Bertolette, Peter, circa 1972-1982 (Box 1)
  - Blattiner, Barbara, 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Blaser, Robin, 1981-1992 (Box 1)
  - Blevins, Richard, 1977-1991; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Includes Court of the Half-King inscribed; Remembering the Future; The Day I Found Marco Polo Outside of Cleveland; and manuscripts.
  - Blitz, Michael, 1983-1993 (Box 1)
  - Bobbitt, Nathaniel, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
    Includes manuscripts.
  - Bogan, Jim, 1980-1990 (Box 1)
  - Borneman, Bill, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Bowen, Robert, 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Braman, Sandra, circa 1992 (Box 1)
  - Brennan, Joe, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Brodsky, Michael, undated (Box 1)
  - Bromige, David, circa 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Bronk, William, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Harvey, undated (Box 1)
  - Buckeye, Bob, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Buttrick, George, 1970-1976; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - C General, 1978-1987 (Box 2)
  - Callahan, Robert, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Bruce, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Chaet, Eric, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
  - Christensen, Paul, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Clark, B. Cass, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Clarke, John, 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Coolidge, Clark, 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Corrigan, Matthew, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Covi, Giovanna, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Creeley, Robert, 1989 (Box 2)
  - D General, 1978-1995 (Box 2)
  - Davenport, Guy, 1976-1982; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Davidson, Michael, circa 1980 (Box 2)
    Includes manuscript.
  - Davies, Allan, 1987 (Box 2)
  - De Felice, James, undated (Box 2)
  - Dewdney, Chistopher, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Dorn, Edward, 1972-1985 (Box 2)
    Includes Bean News, Rolling Stock and manuscripts.
  - Duncan, Robert, 1972-1978 (Box 2)
  - Enslin, Theodore, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Eshleman, Clayton, 1973-1999; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - F General, circa 1980s (Box 2)
  - Ferrini, Vincent, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Friedland, Susan, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Friedlander, Benjamin, 1995-1998 (Box 2)
    Includes the printed works Die Ewigkeit altert and Period Piece.
  - Funkhouser, Chris, 1998 (Box 2)
  - G General, 1972-1991 (Box 2)
  - Gansz, David C.D., 1993 (Box 2)
    Includes printed material.
  - Garber, Eugene K., circa 1980s (Box 2)
  - Gins, Madeline, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Giscombe, Cecil, 1989 (Box 2)
    Includes an enscribed copy of At Large.
  - Gizzi, Michael, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Glover, Albert, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Grenier, Robert, 1980-2000; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Grossinger, Richard, 1971-1985; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - H General, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3)
  - Harrison, Robert, circa 1980s (Box 3)
  - Hatlen, Burton, 1979-1984 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Bobbie Louise, circa 1979-1984 (Box 3)
  - Hejinian, Lyn, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Heller, Michael, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Hickman, Leland, undated (Box 3)
  - Higgins, Dick, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Hollo, Anslem, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Houck, Kemp, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Hough, Lindy, 1972-1986 (Box 3)
  - Howe, Susan, 1983-1987; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Irby, Kenneth, 1972-2002; 12 folders (Box 3)
    Printed and inscribed material included; Archipelago, Etudes. Also includes manuscripts.
  - Jaeger, Sharon Ann, 1980s (Box 4)
  - K General, circa 1980s (Box 4)
  - Kahn, Paul, undated (Box 4)
  - Keane, Jondi, 1970s-1990s; 4 folders (Box 4)
    Includes manuscripts and artwork.
  - Kelly, Robert, 1972-1974 (Box 4)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1978 (Box 4)
  - King, Marth, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Kleiner, Art, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Kornblum, Allen, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Krolich, Jeff, circa 1970s (Box 4)
  - L General, 1980s-1990 (Box 4)
  - Landers, Peter, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Lansing, Gerrit, 1979-2000s; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Laughlin, James, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Leggiere, Phil, circa 1983 (Box 4)
  - Lehman, David, 1983 (Box 4)
  - M General, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
  - Mac Low, Jackson, 1976-1974 (Box 4)
  - Mackey, Nathaniel, 1984-1984 (Box 4)
  - Macleod, Douglas, 1990s (Box 4)
  - Malin, James C. (historian), 1970s-1980s (Box 4)
  - Martin, John (Black Sparrow), 1973 (Box 4)
  - Mason, John, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
  - Matlin, David, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
  - Matthias, John, 1990-1995 (Box 4)
  - Maud, Ralph, 1994 (Box 4)
  - McCaffery, Steve, 1993 (Box 4)
  - McLelland, Bruce, circa 1982 (Box 4)
  - McGann, Jerome, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
  - McNaughton, Duncan, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Messerli, Douglas, 1979-1992 (Box 4)
  - Metcalf, Paul, 1972-1998; 24 folders (Box 4)
  - Meyer, Thomas, circa 1980 (Box 4)
  - Minter, Tom, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Montano, Linda, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Morgan, John, 1971-1986 (Box 4)
  - Moritz, John, circa 1983 (Box 4)
    Includes manuscripts and anotated printed material.
  - N General, 1978-1995 (Box 5)
  - Nowak, Mark, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Nunley, Dick, 1980 (Box 5)
  - O General, circa 1978-1981 (Box 5)
  - O'Brien, Geoffrey, 1980-1986 (Box 5)
  - Olson, Charles, 1964-1967 (Box 5)
    Books by Charles Olson, annotated by Don Byrd.
  - Oppenheimer, Joel, 1979-1984 (Box 5)
    Includes poetry button and various manuscripts.
  - P General, circa 1977-1998 (Box 5)
  - Palmer, Michael, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Paul, Sherman, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Phillips, Dennis, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
  - Plymell, Charles, circa 1985 (Box 5)
  - Pounds, Wayne, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Quartermain, Peter, 1978-1983 (Box 5)
  - Quasha, George, 1980-1987 (Box 5)
  - R General, 1978-1995 (Box 5)
  - Rasula, Jed, 1978-1997; 17 folders (Box 5)
    Includes carbon copies of Don Byrd's responses, as well as 4 issues of The Well Tempered Wreader, May-July 1979.
  - Reese, Marshall and Nora Ligorano, circa 1992-1994 (Box 5)
    Includes CoAccident mailer.
  - Rueckert, William, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Rodefer, Stephen, 1987-1989 (Box 5)
  - Rosenblum, Martin, 1979-1987 (Box 5)
  - Rothschild, Douglas N., 1985-2001 (Box 5)
  - Ryan, Paul, circa 1987-1995 (Box 5)
  - St. James Press, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - S General, 1981-1995 (Box 5)
  - Sanders, Edward, 1982-2002; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes manuscript and Woodstock Journal, October 4-18, 2002.
  - Sharp, Tom, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Schimmel, Harold, circa 1979 (Box 5)
  - Schmitz, Neil, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Schultz, Elizabeth, circa 1973-1986; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Schwerner, Armand, 1983-1987 (Box 5)
  - Sherry, James, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Shoemaker, Lynn, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Silliman, Ron, 1975-1983; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Includes carbon copies from Don Byrd, and manuscripts.
  - Sittnick, Phil, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Patrick, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Skodnick, Roy, 1983-1986 (Box 5)
  - Snyder, Gary, circa 1972 (Box 5)
    Includes Smoky the Bear Sutra, Cottonwood Review, 1972.
  - Stein, Charles, circa 1978-1985 (Box 5)
    Includes manuscripts of "Sound Poems".
  - Strauss, David Levi, circa 1984-1990; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Strauss, David Levi - "Double Portrait of Don & Pierre [Joris], in Darkness & in Light," photograph, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Stroffolino, Chris, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Taggart, John, 1980-1984 (Box 5)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, 1978-1991 (Box 5)
  - Turner, Sam, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Urbanski, Kenneth John, undated (Box 5)
  - Vicuña, Cecilia, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
    Includes Palabra e Hilo / Word & Thread, Morning Star Publications, 1996
  - W General, 1983-1987 (Box 7)
  - Waldman, Annie, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
  - Warsh, Lewis, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Watten, Barrett, 1983-1989; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Weinberger, Eliot, 1981-1985 (Box 7)
  - Weinstein, Norman, circa 1980 (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Mark, 1985-1992 (Box 7)
  - Wellman, Don, 1981-1988; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Wellman, Mac, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Wentworth, Richard, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Wesling, Donald, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Wilk, David (Truck Press), 1974-1978 (Box 7)
  - Willingham, John R., 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Woolf, Douglas, 1973-1977 (Box 7)
    Includes An noun cing / The Collected Letter's of Wolf Run (1976) and an inscribed copy of Had (1977).
  - Y General, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Young, Geoff, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Zweig, Ellen, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified, 1973-1992 (Box 7)
- Sketchbooks and notebooks, 1967-2010; Series II; 2.21; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Sketchbooks and notebooks consist mostly of sketchbooks from the late 1990s and 2000s. Also included are notebooks documenting publishing, exams, and dissertations from the late 1960s through the early 1990s.
  - Publishing record, exams and dissertations, notebooks, 1967-1991; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Notebook, 1998 January 22 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1998 April 26 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1998 November 14-29 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1998 November 29 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1998 December 19 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1999 February 9 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1999 May 24 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1999 October 2 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 1999 October 3 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2000 October 1 (Box 8)
  - China sketchbook, 2000 December 4-18 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, "The Heart Attack Book", 2000 February 11 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2001 January 27 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2001 March 24 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2002 February 24-May 10 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2002 May 10-August 23 (Box 8)
  - Sketchbook, 2002 August 27 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2002 December 26 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2003 October 10 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2003 December (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2004 April (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2004 September (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2005 January (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2005 June (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2005 September (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2006 July 16 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2007 March (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2007 March 27 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2007 August 20 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2009 April 7 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, 2010 June 1 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, circa 2010 (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, undated; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Notebooks, undated; 4 folders (Box 10)
- Photographs, 1970s-1980s; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Color and black and white photographs of poets taken by Don Byrd in the 1970s and 1980s. Photographs include portraits of William Bronk, Don Byrd (self-portrait light drawings), Margie Byrd, Clark Coolidge, Robert Duncan, Gerrit Lansing, Nancy Metcalf, Paul Metcalf, Bernadette Mayer, Tom Meyer, George Quasha, Susan Quasha, Joel Oppenheimer, Gary Synder, Lewis Warsh, and Jonathan Williams.
  - Photographs, 1970s-1980s (Box 11)
- Other papers, 1970s-2010; Series IV; 0.29; (2 boxes)
  Other papers consist of ephemera, postcards, writings, clippings, and a poster.
  - Byrd, Don - Charles Olson's Maximus, circa 1979 (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - The Poetics of Common Knowledge, 1992 (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - Robert Duncan's Medieval Scenes, undated (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - From Notebook: Beijing, 2000 December 4-18 (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - Writing Studies: Notes Toward a Theory of the New Discipline, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - Readings, conferences, etc., circa 1977-1998 (Box 12)
  - Gloucester, Massachusetts, postcards, undated (Box 12)
  - Byrd, Don - Works, assorted, 1980s (Box 12)
  - Assorted, 1970s (Box 12)
  - Joan Michaels, "Donald Byrd", Kite, clipping, 1980 August 27 (Box 12)
  - Giovanna Covi, "Words of Poetry. Words of Theory: At Breakfast with Don Byrd, Robert Creeley, Douglas Gunn, Judith Johnson, Charles Stein, and William Spanos", 1988 (Box 12)
    Photocopy of Boundary 2, Vol. 15/16, Spring/Autumn 1988
  - Ephemera removed from The Great Dimestore Centennial, by Don Byrd, circa 1986 (Box 12)
  - Ephemera removed from Per/ception, edited by Don Wellman, circa 1982 (Box 12)
  - New York State Writers Institute - State University of New York, "The Writer as Teacher", poster, 1992 April 9 (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - "The Visiting Writers Series" 2010-2011, Indiana University - Perdue University Fort, signed poster, circa 2010 (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Michael Blitz, "40. Abstract Words (Abst)," mail art, undated (Box 13 (Oversize))
- Audiovisual materials, 1960s-1990s; 5; 3; (3 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Audiovisual materials consist of recordings made by Don Byrd of poets and friends including John Ashbery, Bruce Andrews, Charles Bernstein, Paul Blackburn, Robin Blaser, Don Byrd, Clark Coolidge, Fielding Dawson, Edward Dorn, Robert Duncan, Robert Grenier, Christer Hennix, Anselm Hollo, Ken Irby, Gerrit Lansing, Jackson MacLow, Paul Metcalf, Charles Olson, Edward Sanders, Gary Snyder, John Yau, Louis Zukofsky, and others.
  - VHS, Video8 cassettes, and Audiotape reels, 1960s-1980s (Box 14)
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Becoming Song", undated; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972837)
    - Blackburn, Paul. "Kalamazoo College", May 27, 1971; Dorn, Ed. April 30, 1974; Creeley, Robert. May 1, 1974, 1971,1974; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972845)
    - "The Cantos of Ezra Pound Mix", undated; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972852)
    - Dorn, Ed. "at Lawrence", "at Albany", 1971,1973 April; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972860)
    - Duncan, Robert. "Charles Olson lectures, University of Iowa", 1978 November 7-8; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972878)
    - "History Teaches; Moog Tongue(?)", undated; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972886)
    - Metcalf, Paul. / Kinnell, Galway. "Albany", 1973 January 29, 1971; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972894)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Rochester", 1982 May 8; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972902)
    - Olson, Charles. "Goddard College", 1965; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972910)
    - Olson, Charles. "Melville lecture, Goddard College", 1965; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972936)
    - Snyder, Gary. "Jewish Community Center, [Albany?]", 1973 November 5; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972928)
    - Stein, Charles. Rasula, Jed. "1980–81" (1 of 2 audiotape reels), 1980-1981; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972951)
    - Stein, Charles. Rasula, Jed. "1980-1981" / "News Cuts", 1980-1981, 1977 June 30; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972944)
    - Sanders, Edward. Stein, Charles / Quasha, George. "Rochester", undated; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972969)
    - Quasha, George / Stein, George. Ladik, Katalin, undated; 1 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002109972977)
    - Bernstein, Charles. "Albany", 1987 October 19; YCALMSS967_0001; 1; 00:43:46 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002093672302)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Reading", undated; YCALMSS967_0002; 1; 00:08:00 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002093672310)
    - Equinox Music. "Bard College", 1990 September 21; YCALMSS967_0003; 1; 01:33:09; At 01:27:00, a movie with Jamie Lee Curtis cuts in until the end. (Box 14, Item barcode 39002093672328)
    - Grenier, Robert."Albany", 1994 October 2; YCALMSS967_0004; 1; 01:21:52 (Box 14, Item barcode 39002093672336)
  - Audiocassettes, 1970s-1990s
    - Lansing, Gerrit., 1997 March; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972381)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Class 2, University at Albany, SUNY", 1984 March 13; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972399)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Class, University at Albany, SUNY", 1984 March 11; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972407)
    - Byrd, Don. "From The Great Dimestore Centennial, University at Albany, SUNY" / Byrd, Don. "Poetry Project", 1982 April 15-1983 May 3; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972415)
    - Andrews, Bruce. Piombino, Nick. "Ear Inn", 1989 April 22; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972423)
    - Mac Low, Jackson. "Open Secrets", undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972431)
    - Stein, Charles. Quasha, George. "Catskill, N.Y.", 1981 August 27; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972449)
    - Mac Low, Jackson. Tardos, Anne. "Songs & Similarities, Tarmac Tapes & Books, Albany", 1985; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972456)
      A list of contents is included.
      A note inscribed on the audiocassette reads: For Don with best wishes, Anne and Jackson, 9/26/86
      A Vocabulary for Anne Tardos, 1980
      Syllables, 1985
      Octet for a Sunset, 1985
      Heterophony, 1984 from "Hereford Bosons 1"
      Aum Gatha, 1982
      Real Sleeper, Real Dreamer, 1976
      Tara Gatha, 1975
      Phonemicon from "Hereford Bosons 1", 1984
      Figure and Escape, 1985
    - Coolidge, Clark. / Stein, Charles. Byrd, Don., 1990 February; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972464)
    - Grenier, Robert. Rasula, Jed. Byrd, Don. "Berkeley", 1987 May 11; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972472)
    - Duncan, Robert. "Albany", undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972480)
    - Stein, Charles. "Albany", 1984 April 26; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972498)
    - Mac Low, Jackson. (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 October 30; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972506)
    - Mac Low, Jackson. (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1984 October 30; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972514)
    - Dorn, Ed. "Albany", undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972522)
    - Mackey, Nate. "Song of the Andoumboulou" / "Tanganyika Strut"-KUSP, 1995, 1987 August 20; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972688)
    - Dunlop, Nancy and Yates, Katie. "sea lion we are not followed here" with music by Laurie Anderson, "Albany Art Gallery"; Byrd, Don. Sanders, Ed. Owens, Derek, et al., "Paradise/Play" / Sanders, Ed. The Rebel Café "Readings Against the End of the World", 1992 March 20-25; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972696)
    - Sanders, Ed. "Albany" / Funkhouser, Chris. "Cesaria Evora reading", 1997 May 1; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972704)
    - Dorn, Ed. "Alternative radio program, introduced and with commentary by Anselm Hollo", 2000 May; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972712)
    - Irby, Ken. "Reading at home of Steve Dickison, Berkeley", recorded by Kush of Cloud House Poetry Archives, 1999 August 1; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972720)
    - Irby, Ken."Bard College, A Set", 1994 May 9; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972738)
    - Coolidge, Clark. "Polaroid" II, III, undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972746)
    - Coolidge, Clark. "Polaroid" Pt. I / Mac Low, Jackson. "Black Tarantula"; Hausmann, Raoul., undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972753)
    - Irby, Ken. "Reading new work at Bard College" / "Reading Mary Butts at Bard College", 1984 May 8; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972761)
    - Coolidge, Clark. "St. Mark's Church" / Reznikoff, Charles. "St. Mark's Church", 1973 October 17 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972779)
    - Zukofsky, Louis. "Bard College", 1960s; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972787)
    - Coolidge, Clark. "Bard College", 1984 April 15; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972795)
    - Lansing, Gerrit. Irby, Ken Irby. "Ear Inn", 1987 December 12; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972803)
    - Dawson, Fielding. "St. Mark's Church" / McClure, Michael. "St. Mark's Church", 1971 April 21, 1973 March 7; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972811)
    - Giscombe, Cecil., undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972829)
    - Lansing, Gerrit. / Feidt, Thorpe. "Leibniz book", 1963 December 18-1989; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972233)
      A list of contents includes: "Judgement of the City", "Festival Song", and "The Green Bottle"
    - McCaffery, Steve. "Wot We Wukkers Want, Midnight Peace, A Hundred / Eigner, Larry. "Poems", undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972241)
      A list of poems is included.
      1. Dying
      2. A Structural F[?]
      3. A Temporary Language
      4. Love Children
      5. Magnetic Lines
      6. Common Sense
      7. Tolsto[?] Kept On
      8. To Negotiate
      9. Music is Human
      10. Unyielding Rock
      11. Paper
      12. The Sky
      13. Snow Flakes
      14. Trees Stand
      15. Time Flies
      16. Birds
      17. How Much a Squirrel
      18. The Sun Goes On
      19. The Cat's Ears
      20. You Gotta Have Steam
      21. At Death Olson's
      22. Tribute to Cage
      23. Around the Frames
      24. Open Road
      25. Enough Now
      26. Contact Communication
      27. Everybody Dies
    - Grenier, Robert. Rasula, Jed. Byrd, Don. "Berkeley" / Weber, Ben. "Symposium on Poems of Blake", 1987 May 11, undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972258)
      Contents listed on the symposium of Blake's poems include: "To Autumn", "Never Seek: Tell Thy Love", "Mad Sorts", and "To Spring".
    - Blaser, Robin. "Cambridge" (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993 September 19; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972266)
    - Blaser, Robin. "Reading" (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993 September 19; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972274)
    - Brown. Clarke. Keil., undated; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972282)
    - Hollo, Anselm. "Bard College", 1984 August 3; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972290)
    - Duncan, Robert. "Albany" / Duncan, Robert and Sanders, Ed "at Don Byrd's", 1982 October 19, October 16; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972308)
    - McClelland, Bruce. "Albany" / "Sound-Text Festivals", 1981 November; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972316)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Class, University at Albany, SUNY", 1984 March 22; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972324)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Class, University at Albany, SUNY", 1984 March 20; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972332)
    - Metcalf, Paul. "Class 1, University at Albany, SUNY", 1984 March 8; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972340)
    - Duncan, Robert. "Bard College", 1982 October 12; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972357)
    - Duncan, Robert. "Bard College", 1982 October 5; 1 (Box 15, Item barcode 39002109972365)